So let's compare the Perceptron algorithm and the Gradient Descent algorithm.
我们来对比感知器算法和梯度下降算法
In the Gradient Descent algorithm,
在梯度下降算法中
we take the weights and change them from Wi to
我们得到权重 从 Wi 改为
Wi_ plus_ alpha_ times_ Y hat_ minus_ Y_ times_ Xi.
Wi + α (y -y-hat) Xi
In the Perceptron algorithm,
在感知器算法中
not every point changes weights,
并不是每个点改变权重
only the misclassified ones.
只有分类错误的点
Here, if X is misclassified,
如果 x 被误分类
we'll change the weights by adding Xi to Wi if the point label is positive,
如果点的标签为正 我们会把 Xi 加上 Wi 来改变权重
and subtracting if negative.
如果为负 就要减去
Now the question is, are these two things the same?
现在问题是这两个是相同的吗？
Well, let's remember that in that Perceptron algorithm,
我们回忆下在感知器算法中
the labels are one and zero.
标签是 0 和 1
And the predictions Y-hat are also one and zero.
预测 Y-hat 也是 0 和 1
So, if the point is correct, classified,
如果点是正确分类的
then Y_ minus_ Y-hat is zero because Y is equal to Y-hat.
那么 y- y-hat 为 0 因为 y 等于 y-hat
Now, if the point is labeled blue,
如果点为蓝色
then Y_ equals_ one.
那么 y 等于 1
And if it's misclassified,
如果是错误分类的
then the prediction must be Y-hat_ equals_ zero.
那么预测为 y-hat = 0
So Y-hat_ minus_ Y is minus one.
y-hat - y 等于 -1
Similarly, with the points labeled red,
类似地 点标记为红色
then Y_ equals_ zero and Y-hat_ equals_ one.
那么 y = 0 而且 y-hat = 1
So, Y-hat_ minus_ Y_ equals_ one.
那么 y-hat - y 等于 1
This may not be super clear right away.
这可能不会立即很清晰
But if you stare at the screen for long enough,
不过如果你长时间注视着屏幕
you'll realize that the right and the left are exactly the same thing.
你会发现右侧和左侧完全相同
The only difference is that in the left,
唯一的不同在于左侧
Y-hat can take any number between zero and one,
Y-hat 是 0 到 1 之间的任何数字
whereas in the right,
而在右侧
Y-hat can take only the values zero or one.
Y-hat 只能是数字 0 或 1
It's pretty fascinating, isn't it?
非常有趣 对不对？
But let's study Gradient Descent even more carefully.
我们来更加认真地学习梯度下降
Both in the Perceptron algorithm and the Gradient Descent algorithm,
在感知器算法和梯度下降算法中
a point that is misclassified tells a line to come closer because eventually,
这个被误分类的点让一条线段更加靠近
it wants the line to surpass it so it can be in the correct side.
因为最终它想要这条线段越过它 这样可以处于正确的一侧
Now, what happens if the point is correctly classified?
如果点被正确分类 会发生什么呢？
Well, the Perceptron algorithm says do absolutely nothing.
感知器算法表示什么都不做
In the Gradient Descent algorithm,
在梯度下降算法中
you are changing the weights.
你可以改变权重
But what is it doing?
可是如何做到呢？
Well, if we look carefully,
如果我们仔细观察
what the point is telling the line,
这个点要求这条直线
is to go farther away.
移动到更远的地方
And this makes sense, right?
这样说得通 对不对？
Because if you're correctly classified,
因为如果正确分类
say, if you're a blue point in the blue region,
也就是说 蓝点位于蓝色区域
you'd like to be even more into the blue region,
可能更容易进入蓝色区域
so your prediction is even closer to one,
预测值更接近 1
and your error is even smaller.
误差更小
Similarly, for a red point in the red region.
同样 红点位于红色区域
So it makes sense that the point tells the line to go farther away.
这个点要求这条直线远离是说得通的
And that's precisely what the Gradient Descent algorithm does.
这就是梯度下降算法的用途
The misclassified points asks the line to come closer and
误分类的点要求直线更加靠近
the correctly classified points asks the line to go farther away.
而正确分类的点要求直线远离
The line listens to all the points and takes steps in
这条直线结合所有点的要求 然后按照这种方式移动
such a way that it eventually arrives to a pretty good solution.
最后达到相当良好的解决方案